Guide to the James McCourt and Vincent Virga Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James McCourt and Vincent Virga papers
1941-2011
GEN MSS 845
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
53.21
(66 boxes)
The collection consists of writings, journals, correspondence, printed material, photographs, audiovisual material, computer disks, and other papers documenting the literary careers and lives of James McCourt and Vincent Virga.
McCourt, James, 1941-
Virga, Vincent
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 65 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 66 (audiovisual material): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
James McCourt (1941-)
James McCourt was born July 4, 1941, in New York, NY. He was educated at Manhattan College (B.A., 1962), New York University (1962-1964), and Yale University, School of Drama (1964-1965). McCourt is the author of the novels Mawrdew Czgowchz (1975), Delancey's Way (2000), and Now Voyagers: The Night Sea Journey (2007), several collections of short stories, and Queer Street (2003), a work of nonfiction documenting the story of 20th-century gay culture. He has also published work in The New Yorker and The Paris Review.
Vincent Virga
Vincent Virga was born September 28, 1942, in New York, NY. He was educated at St. Bonaventure University, (B.A., 1964) and Yale University (1964-1965). Virga is an editor, writer, and author of the novels Gaywyck (1980), A Comfortable Corner (1982), and Vadriel Vail (2001). He has been McCourt's partner since their time as graduate students at Yale.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, journals, correspondence, printed material, photographs, audiovisual material, computer disks, and other papers documenting the literary careers and lives of James McCourt and Vincent Virga.
McCourt's writings comprise the bulk of the collection, and include notes, notebooks, manuscript and typescript drafts, correspondence, and printed material related to his published works: Mawrdew Czgowchwz (1975), Kaye Wayfaring in "Avenged:" Four Stories (1984), Time Remaining: Stories (1993), Delancey's Way (2000), Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (2002), Queer Street: Rise and Fall of American Culture, 1947-1985 (2004), and Now Voyagers: The Night Sea Journey (2007). Virga's writings consist of manuscript and typescript drafts of his published works, including Gaywyck (1980), Comfortable Corner (1982), and Vadriel Vale (2001).
Diaries, appointment calendars, and notebooks, belonging to both McCourt and Virga and spanning over thirty years, document their individual careers and their life together. McCourt's journal from July 1973 to December 1978 covers his efforts to sell Mawrdew Czgowchz, and his journals from 1992 to 1995 contain notes for Time Out of Mind and Delancey's Way. Other material relating to the personal and professional lives of McCourt and Virga include: personal correspondence between McCourt and Virga; professional correspondence with publishers, editors, and agents; photographs of McCourt and Virga; McCourt's childhood memorabilia; and printed material.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. James McCourt Writings. II. Vincent Virga Writings. III. Diaries, Appointment Calendars, and Notebooks. IV. Personal and Professional Papers.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Gay authors; Gay men; Homosexuality and literature; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Sound recordings; Audiocassettes; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; LGBTQ resource; McCourt, James, 1941-; Virga, Vincent
- James McCourt Writings, Series I; 19.42; (20 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Files are not arranged in any particular order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 66 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - McCourt typed copy - Three ballads (Box 1)
  - "Panache" source material; Venice - commeddia, Summer 1966, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Killing Time: 16 days Grand Jury log (Box 1)
  - "Panache": first rough draft (Box 1)
  - Farce 1966 (Box 1)
  - Panache: notes & scenes (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 1)
  - The End Prom, A Sonnett to Madge for April Fool, Beverly Dawn (Box 1)
  - Schlock: an evening in the theatre (Box 1)
  - Endymion and the Moon (Box 1)
  - Panache screenplay (Box 1)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 1)
  - Aurora and Swan (Box 1)
  - "It was only a question of the children..." (Box 1)
  - Miriam and David in January (Box 1)
  - Ballad of Twitching Bois, Act II (Box 1)
  - Not to Worry (It'll All Come Out) (Box 1)
  - Ninevey (Box 1)
  - Panache (Box 1)
  - Panache, Final copy (Box 1)
  - Notes, clippings, ephemera (Box 1)
  - Isabel Briggs Myers Type Indicator Test (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Notes, 3 (Box 1)
  - The Love that Dare not Speak... (Box 1)
  - The Edge of Night (Box 2)
  - Notes, 2 (Box 2)
  - Scenes of a New York Night (Box 2)
  - Time Out of Mind
  - Time Remaining (Box 2)
  - The Pathetique (Box 2)
  - Ensenada (Box 2)
  - Time Remaining
  - Remembrance
  - Histrionics
  - Remembrance
  - The Four Green Fields
  - Principal Photography
  - The Pathetique
  - Do the Work as It Was Meant...
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 2)
  - Time Out of Mind
  - New Yorker short stories
  - Notes (Box 2)
  - Immortal She
  - Histrionics
  - Delancey's Way
  - Mawrdew Czgowchz
  - Histrionics (Box 2)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (Box 2)
  - All About Everyone
  - Something Sensational to Read on the Train
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake, 1982-1983
  - Histrionics
  - I Go Back to the Mais Oui
  - In Case It is
  - In Tir nan Og
  - Pathetique / Time Remaining
  - Time Out of Mind
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz, 5 (Box 2)
  - For Yonder Breaks, Stored in: Oversize Box 57
  - David?: a story by Julianne Virga (Box 2)
  - Time Remaining (Box 2)
  - Programs of dramatic performances (Box 2)
  - Music score, clippings (Box 2)
  - For Yonder Breaks (Box 2)
  - Panache (Box 2)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 2)
  - Essay on Jeanne Engels: an Open Letter on a Vagrant Star (Box 3)
  - Birthday card (Box 3)
  - Queuers (Box 3)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz, 3 (Box 3)
  - Panache (Box 3)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 3)
  - The File on Kaye Wayfaring (Box 3)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 3)
  - Reviews (Box 3)
  - A Sonnet for August (Box 3)
  - Alfred A. Knopf catalog (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (empty folder) (Box 3)
  - Holly Woodlawn (Box 3)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (empty envelope) (Box 3)
  - 1965-1967 (1968 end July) incl. Czgowchwz notes, Eliza I note (Box 3)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz, 10 (Box 3)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (continued), 7 (Box 4)
  - Manhattan College Players present in Smith Auditorium... Charley's Aunt...
  - Kaye Wayfaring in "Avenged", 2 (Box 4)
  - Laird & Contino (Box 4)
  - The Scan of Illyria (Box 4)
  - Something Sensational to Read in the Train (Box 4)
  - Gayweir (Box 4)
  - Four Stories of Midwinter (Box 4)
  - Vissi d'Arte (Box 4)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 5)
  - Notes (Box 5)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 5)
  - Boston Back Bay Blackout Beguine (Box 5)
  - Aurora & Swan (Box 5)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 5)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 5)
  - An Open Letter on a Vagrant Star / Jeanne Eagels (Box 5)
  - Pelleas et Melisande (Box 5)
  - Jeanne Eagel's Revelation (Box 5)
  - Bags by Fran Chesleigh (Box 5)
  - The Scan of Illyria, 2 (Box 5)
  - Illyria (Box 5)
  - Kaye Wayfaring in "Avenged", 2 (Box 5)
  - The Scan of Illyria (Box 5)
  - Kindly Midwinter Meeting (Box 5)
  - The Voyage of Genesis (Box 5)
  - The Nature of Affection (Box 5)
  - I Go Back to the Mais Oui (Box 5)
  - In Tir nan Og (Box 5)
  - I Go Back to the Mais Oui (Box 5)
  - In Tir nan Og (Box 5)
  - I Go Back to the Mais Oui, The Mind of James McCourt by J.D. McClatchy (Box 5)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (Box 5)
  - In the Land of Tir na Nog (Box 5)
  - Time Remaining (Box 5)
  - Under Nephim (Box 5)
  - Book contract (Box 5)
  - Illusions; words and music by Frederick Hollander (Box 5)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 5)
  - The Early Rising Sequence (Box 5)
  - The Sky in December (Box 5)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 5)
  - The Voyage of Genesis (Box 5)
  - Notes (Box 5)
  - The National Library of Ireland (Box 5)
  - The Scan of Illyria (Box 5)
  - Ensenada (Box 5)
  - Printed material, notes (Box 5)
  - Notes (Box 5)
  - Mart Crowley: the Algonquin Hotel (Box 5)
  - Panache (Box 5)
  - Time Remaining (Box 6)
  - 'For Yonder Breaks' and 'Should Old Acquaintance' (Box 6)
  - Time Remaining (Box 6)
  - Intolerance (Box 6)
  - Printed material (Box 6)
  - The Tunnel: a Novel; by William H. Gass (Box 6)
  - Time Out of Mind
  - Eternal Boy (Box 6)
  - Remembrance (Box 6)
  - Romance (Box 6)
  - What Might Have Been: a film (Box 6)
  - Winter Meeting (Box 6)
  - Principal Photography (Box 6)
  - Now Voyagers (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Time Remaining (Box 6)
  - Printed material, 2 (Box 6)
  - Clippings and notes (Box 6)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 6)
  - Seven Monologues for the Climax of Snow Country
  - Time Out of Mind, 2 (Box 6)
  - I for One (Box 6)
  - Principal Photography (Box 6)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 6)
  - Voyage of Genesis (Box 6)
  - Lycidas (Box 6)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 6)
  - Time Out of Mind (continued) (Box 7)
  - Histrionics (Box 7)
  - Delancey's Way (Box 7)
  - Histrionics (Box 7)
  - Something Sensational to Read in the Train (Box 7)
  - Delancy (his book) (Box 7)
  - Printed material (Box 7)
  - Kaye (Box 7)
  - Notes (Box 7)
  - The Fabulous (Box 7)
  - Notebook (empty) (Box 7)
  - Le Chant du Cygne / Undertow (Box 7)
  - Printed material (Box 7)
  - This Time (Box 7)
  - Bette Davis Interview (Box 7)
  - Victoria de los Angeles, 2 (Box 7)
  - I, I, Me, Me, I, Me, I (Jameson) (Box 8)
  - Mimesis (Box 8)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 8)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 8)
  - Time Remaining, 6 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Evening (Box 8)
  - Writing: What I'm Going to Do I Think (Box 8)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 8)
  - Notes (Box 8)
  - Printed material (Box 8)
  - Mnemosyne by Isabel Miller (Box 8)
  - Relatively coordinated are the mimesis... (Box 8)
  - Alice Crimmins' Odyssey (Box 8)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 8)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 8)
  - Summer Buses, Summer Fugues (Box 8)
  - Time Remaining, 2 (Box 8)
  - Immortal She (Box 8)
  - Printed material (Box 8)
  - The file on Time Remaining (Box 9)
  - Lucifer (Box 9)
  - Victoria de los Angeles, 3 (Box 9)
  - Dublin, the Liberties (Box 9)
  - Lucifer (Box 9)
  - Clowns adrift in gossamer... (Box 9)
  - Clippings (Box 9)
  - Writings (Box 9)
  - Onnagata (Box 9)
  - Le Chant du Cygne (Swan Song) (Box 9)
  - The Voyage of Genesis (Box 9)
  - Printed material, 3 (Box 9)
  - The Voyage of Genesis (Box 9)
  - I Go Back to the Mais Oui, 2 (Box 9)
  - The Nature of Affection, 2 (Box 9)
  - Time Remaining, 3 (Box 10)
  - Jameson, 4 (Box 10)
  - "Best Friends": 5 notebooks, 5 (Box 10)
  - We Live by Night (Box 10)
  - Jameson (Box 10)
  - Jameson (continued) (Box 11)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 11)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 11)
  - Time Remaining (Box 11)
  - Lasting City (Box 11)
  - Hellbent (Box 11)
  - Intolerance (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 11)
  - Victoria de los Angeles, 4 (Box 11)
  - Scan of Illyria (Box 11)
  - New York Lit Up by Night (Box 11)
  - Patrick Kavanagh (Box 11)
  - At Max's Kansas City (Box 11)
  - Star Soul (Box 11)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (Box 11)
  - Laura Rubin (Box 11)
  - Anymore (Box 11)
  - You Want to Know Why I Drink (Box 11)
  - Sarris, etc. (Box 11)
  - Diane de Vors (Box 11)
  - Mawrdew cast list (Box 11)
  - Best Friends (Box 11)
  - Time Out of Mind (Box 12)
  - Romance, 2 (Box 12)
  - Various writings (Box 12)
  - Moira Orfei in Aigues-Mortes by Wayne Koestenbaum (Box 12)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz in Dublin (Box 12)
  - Time Remaining (Box 12)
  - Printed material (Box 12)
  - "JM interview with Bette Davies for AFI" (microcassettes) (Box 66)
    Scope and Contents
    1 folder, 9 audiocassettes
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Untitled, undated; 1; This microcassette was found to be blank. No digitized files were created. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361801)
    - Maurial Foley, GSA, undated; 1; 00:51:37; The program ends abruptly. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361819)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; This microcassette was found to be blank. No digitized files were created. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361827)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:18:56; The program is distorted at times and it begins abruptly. Side B is blank. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361835)
      The recording is of a musical performance featuring a choir and accompanying piano.
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:31:06 (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361843)
      The recording is of a musical performance featuring a singer and accompanying piano.
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:55:54; The program is distorted at times. There is a gap in programming on side B at 20:36-23:11. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361850)
      The recording is of a musical performance featuring a singer and accompanying piano. A man and woman is also heard speaking to each other towards the end of sides A and B. Another man, speaking in English, is also heard at times.
    - Leonard Mark Anderson, undated; 1; 00:52:59; There is a high level of background noise on the cassette. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361868)
    - Henry Mau[?] (Hauls Sland: "Une dis [?]), undated; 1; 01:02:48; The program begins abruptly and there is a high level of background noise on the cassette. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361876)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; This microcassette was found to be blank. No digitized files were created. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361884)
  - Kaye Wayfaring in "Avenged", 2 (Box 12)
  - Kaye Wayfaring in "Avenged" (continued), 3 (Box 13)
  - We Live by Night (Box 13)
  - What Might Have Been (Box 13)
  - An Open Letter on a Vagrant Star (Box 13)
  - Queer Street, 10 (Box 13)
  - Queer Street (continued), 4 (Box 14)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (Box 14)
  - Delancey's Way (Box 14)
  - Queer Street, 6 (Box 14)
  - Queer Street (continued), 2004; 13 (Box 15)
    2 computer disks
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services:
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0001. Bookworm. Prod/Host: Michael Silverblat featuring: James McCourt I
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0013. Bookworm. Prod/Host: Michael Silverblat featuring: James MCourt identity
  - Queer Street (continued), 10 (Box 16)
  - The Opera, 4 (Box 16)
  - Now Voyagers, 7 (Box 17)
  - Time Remaining (Box 17)
  - Queer Street, 2 (Box 17)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake, 5 (Box 17)
  - New York Review Books catalog (Box 17)
  - Knopf 2002 catalog (Box 17)
  - Pathetique, 2 (Box 17)
  - Pathetique (continued) (Box 18)
  - A Plethora (Box 18)
  - Driven Woman (Box 18)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake, 3 (Box 18)
  - Delancey's Way (Box 18)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz, 3 (Box 18)
  - Delancey's Way (Box 18)
  - Delancey's Way (continued), 4 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous writings (Box 19)
  - Lasting City (Box 19)
  - Lasting City, Histrionics (Box 19)
  - Ventriloquies (Box 19)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (Box 19)
  - Queer Street (Box 19)
  - October for Idas by Star Black (Box 19)
  - Notes, printed material (Box 19)
  - Writings by J.D. McClatchy (Box 19)
  - Now Voyagers (Box 19)
  - Mae West (Box 19)
  - Notes, 2 (Box 19)
  - Of Moths and Mercury by Tom DiTusa, 4 (Box 19)
  - The Old Lag by Matthew Fink (Box 19)
  - Broken Goddess (Box 20)
  - A Plethora (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 20)
  - Mae West (Box 20)
  - Afterword for James Schuyler's 'What's For Dinner?', 2 (Box 20)
- Vincent Virga Writings, Series II; 5; (5 boxes)
  Box 66 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Priapics (Box 21)
  - Michael (Box 21)
  - A Comfortable Corner, 4 (Box 21)
  - Kirov book proposal (Box 21)
  - Picasso: creator and destroyer by Arianna Stassinopoulos (Box 21)
  - The Eighties: Images of America (dust jacket)
  - Gotham (Box 21)
    1 folder, 1 computer disk
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0012.
  - Eyes of the Nation, 3
    Audiovisual material is contained in Box 66. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Eyes of the Nation" (Box 21)
      Related Materials
      There is a videocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 66.
    - "Eyes of the Nation", clips (videocassette), 1999 April 1; 1; 01:57:45; Channel 1 and 2 are mono. There is a visible timecode that appears on part of the program. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361702)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be available. Consult Access Services for further information.
      This videocassette is related to two folders of material found in Box 21.
  - A Comfortable Corner
  - Carthographia, 2007
  - The Book of Deals (Box 21)
  - Printed material (Box 21)
  - Vadriel Vale (Box 21)
  - A Comfortable Corner (Box 21)
  - A Comfortable Corner (continued) (Box 22)
  - Short stories (Box 22)
  - A Comfortable Corner (Box 22)
  - Gaywyck (Box 22)
  - A Comfortable Corner (Box 22)
  - Gaywyck (Box 22)
  - Gaywyck (continued), 2 (Box 23)
  - Vadriel Vale (Box 23)
  - Gaywyck, 6 (Box 23)
  - Vadriel Vale (Box 23)
  - Gaywyck, 2 (Box 23)
  - Theatricals (Box 23)
  - Gaywyck (Box 23)
  - Gaywyck (continued), 3 (Box 24)
  - The Eighties: Images of America, 6 (Box 24)
  - A Comfortable Corner (Box 24)
  - A Comfortable Corner (continued) (Box 25)
  - Early Ripe, 5 (Box 25)
    1 computer disk
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0002. Vincent Virga; Early Ripe: a novel
  - Pound Net
  - Vadriel Vail, 4 (Box 25)
  - Eyes of the Nation (Box 25)
  - Carthographia (Box 25)
  - Gaywyck dust jacket (Box 25)
  - Early Ripe (Box 25)
  - Short stories (Box 25)
  - Trifles (Box 25)
  - Herald Angel (Box 25)
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0003. Vincent Virga; Herald Angel: a novel
- Diaries, Appointment Calendars, and Notebooks, Series III; 9; (9 boxes)
  Organized by creator and then arranged chronologically.
  Box 66 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies available upon request. Consult Access Services for information.
  - James McCourt, 1969-1989; 2 (Box 26)
    - McCourt Dublin notebook, 1987 (Box 26)
    - John O'Conor (microcassette), 1987; 1; 00:07:50; The program begins abruptly and gradually fades out. Side B is blank. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361892)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies available upon request. Consult Access Services for further information.
      This microcassette is related to a folder of material titled "McCourt Dublin notebook" in Box 26.
  - James McCourt, 1990-1995; 11 (Box 27)
  - James McCourt, 1998-2002; 6 (Box 28)
  - James McCourt, 2003-2008; 10 (Box 29)
  - Vincent Virga, 1957-1982; 15 (Box 30)
  - Vincent Virga, 1985-1995; 5 (Box 31)
  - Vincent Virga, 1994-2000; 10 (Box 32)
  - Vincent Virga, 2001-2004; 13 (Box 33)
  - Vincent Virga, 2004-2009; 10 (Box 34)
- Personal and Professional Papers, Series IV; 16; (16 boxes)
  - McCourt correspondence, 1969-1989; 8 (Box 35)
  - Letter from McCourt and Virga to YDS (Box 35)
  - Virga's International Certificates of Vaccination (Box 35)
  - Virga correspondence (Box 35)
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 35)
  - Catholic Forensic League Certificate (Box 35)
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 36)
  - Memorabilia (Box 36)
  - Guest lecture material (Box 36)
  - Carthographia talk (Box 36)
  - Letter to Larry Pomer (Box 36)
  - Virga correspondence (Box 36)
  - Jay Birdsong (Box 36)
  - Birga business correspondence (Box 36)
  - Letter from Tom Carey to Virga (Box 36)
  - Blazing Heart Garbonzo Productions (Box 36)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 36)
  - Correspondence between McCourt and Virga, 2 (Box 36)
  - Virga business correspondence (Box 36)
  - Postcard from McCourt to Robert and Pamela (Box 36)
  - Letter from Maria Callas to McCourt (Box 36)
  - Memorabilia (Box 36)
  - Letters from Harold Brodsky to McCourt (Box 36)
  - British visa cards, 1971 (Box 36)
  - Correspondence between McCourt and the Dalkey Archive Press (Box 36)
  - Plane tickets (Box 36)
  - McCourt book contracts (Box 36)
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 37)
  - Correspondence between McCourt and Virga (Box 37)
  - Eyes of the Nation agreements (Box 37)
  - Letters from McCourt to William Corley (Box 37)
  - Bonadieu, 1961-1964; 3 (Box 38)
  - Virga correspondence (Box 38)
    There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 66.
  - All Things Considered, "Gay Gothic", 1981 March 24; 1; 00:06:15; Side B is blank. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361918)
    This audiocassette is related to a folder of material titled "Virga Correspondence" in Box 38.
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 38)
  - McCourt reviews (Box 39)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz
  - Virga correspondence, 8 (Box 39)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 39)
  - Virga correspondence, 4 (Box 39)
  - Virga correspondence (continued) (Box 40)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 40)
  - Virga correspondence, 10 (Box 40)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 40)
  - Virga correspondence, 2 (Box 40)
  - Virga correspondence (continued), 9 (Box 41)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (Box 41)
  - McCourt notes
    Box 66 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - McCourt notes (Box 41)
      There are nine microcassettes related to this material found in Box 66.
    - Rena Holohan, "The Irish Times" (microcassette), undated; 1; 00:52:56; There is high background noise on the cassette. The program ends abruptly. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361710)
      This microcassette is related to material title "McCourt notes" found in Box 41.
    - Vonc[?] Dawling (microcassette), undated; 1; 00:29:46; There is high background noise on the cassette. The program ends abruptly. Side B is blank. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361728)
    - Untitled (microcassette), undated; 1; This microcassette was found to be blank. No digitized files were created. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361736)
    - Marie Ilean (microcassette), undated; 1; 00:39:52; There is high background noise on the cassette. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361744)
    - Daniel [?] Valmulk[?] (microcassette), undated; 1; 00:49:19; There is high background noise on the cassette. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361751)
    - Homan Patterson (microcassette), undated; 1; 00:43:29; There is high background noise on the cassette. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361769)
    - Untitled (microcassette), undated; 1; 01:01:45; There is high background noise on the cassette. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361777)